<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>

    <string name="name">KBCV</string>

    <!-- labels -->
    <string name="equations">Equations</string>
    <string name="rules">Rules</string>
    <string name="functions">Functions</string>
    <string name="variables">Variables</string>
    <string name="symbols">Symbols</string>
    <string name="arity">arity</string>
    <string name="automatic_completion">Automatic completion</string>
    <string name="computing">Computing&#8230;</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="undo">undo</string>
    <string name="done">done</string>
    <string name="save">save</string>
    <string name="add">add</string>
    <string name="clear">clear</string>

    <!-- dialogs -->
    <string name="add_es">Add ES</string>
    <string name="as_new">Use as new ES</string>
    <string name="add_to">Add to existing ES</string>

    <string name="new_fun">New Function</string>
    <string name="err_empty">You have to enter something</string>
    <string name="err_symbol_exists">Symbol already exists</string>
    <string name="err_nan">No valid number</string>
    <string name="new_var">New Variable</string>

    <string name="undo_dialog">Undo/Redo History</string>

    <string name="import_dialog">Import ES</string>
    <string name="import_external">Import from external file</string>
    <string name="select_filemanager">Select a File Manager</string>
    <string name="err_filemanager">Please install a File Manager</string>

    <string name="hint_name">name</string>
    <string name="save_trs">Save TRS</string>
    <string name="saved_as">Saved rules as %1$s in %2$s</string>

    <!-- error messages -->
    <string name="error_simplify">Nothing to simplify</string>
    <string name="error_delete">Nothing to delete</string>
    <string name="error_compose">Nothing to compose</string>
    <string name="error_collapse">Nothing to collapse</string>
    <string name="error_deduce">Nothing deduced</string>
    <string name="error_auto_complete">Automatic completion not successful</string>
    <string name="error_precedence">Could not add to precedence</string>
    <string name="error_remove_precedence">Could not remove precedence</string>
    <string name="error_orient">Equation could not be oriented</string>
    <string name="error_complete">TRS is not complete yet</string>

    <!-- ok messages -->
    <string name="ok_orient"><b>orient:</b> %1$d equations oriented</string>
    <string name="ok_simplify"><b>simplify:</b> some equations simplified</string>
    <string name="ok_delete"><b>delete:</b> %1$d equations deleted</string>
    <string name="ok_compose"><b>compose:</b> some rules composed</string>
    <string name="ok_collapse"><b>collapse:</b> some rules collapsed</string>
    <string name="ok_deduced"><b>deduce:</b> %1$d new equations deduced</string>
    <string name="ok_added_es"><b>added ES:</b> %1$d new equations added</string>
    <string name="ok_new_es"><b>new ES:</b> %1$d new equations</string>
    <string name="ok_auto_complete">Automatic completion successful</string>
    <string name="ok_added_precedence">Added %1$s to precedence</string>
    <string name="removed_precedence">Removed precedence</string>
    <string name="edited_precedence">Edited precedence</string>
    <string name="added_var">Added a variable</string>
    <string name="added_fun">Added a function symbol</string>
    <string name="removed_eq">Removed equation %1$d</string>
    <string name="edited_eq">Edited equation %1$d</string>
    <string name="edited_prec">Edited Precedence</string>
    <string name="created_eq">Created new equation</string>
    <string name="complete">TRS is complete now!</string>
    <string name="clear_all">cleared all</string>
    <string name="initialize">initialize</string>
    <string name="simplify_delete">Simplified equation %1$d as far as possible</string>

    <!-- settings -->
    <string name="rounds">rounds in automatic completion</string>
    <string name="variable_symbols">Variable Symbols</string>
    <string name="function_symbols">Function Symbols</string>
    <string name="variable_summary">Variable names displayed in radial picker: </string>
    <string name="function_summary">Function names displayed in radial picker: </string>
    <string name="error_symbols">Radial Layout can only display 6 symbols, more will be ignored</string>

    <string name="drawer_open">drawer open</string>
    <string name="drawer_close">drawer close</string>

    <string name="section_format">Page %1$d</string>
    <string name="completion">Completion</string>
    <string name="completion_long_text">Interactively apply the inference rules of Knuth-Bendix Completion</string>
    <string name="equation_editor">Equation Editor</string>
    <string name="equation_long_text">Define and edit your own equational systems</string>
    <string name="precedences">Precedences</string>
    <string name="precedence">Precedence</string>
    <string name="history">History</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="precedences_long_text">Supply your own LPO precedence or let the app figure it out for you</string>
    <!-- colored example equations-->
    <string name="eq1">
        <![CDATA[<font color=#eeeedd>f</font>(<font color=#eeeedd>f</font>(<font color=#4C804C>x</font>, <font color=#4C804C>y</font>), <font color=#4C804C>z</font>)
        → <font color=#eeeedd>f</font>(<font color=#4C804C>x</font>, <font color=#eeeedd>f</font>(<font color=#4C804C>y</font>, <font color=#4C804C>z</font>))]]>
    </string>

    <string name="eq2">
        <![CDATA[<font color=#eeeedd>f</font>(<font color=#4C804C>x</font>, <font color=#eeeedd>c</font>)
        → <font color=#4C804C>x</font>]]>
    </string>

    <string name="eq3">
        <![CDATA[<font color=#eeeedd>f</font>(<font color=#4C804C>x</font>, <font color=#eeeedd>g</font>(<font color=#4C804C>x</font>))
        → <font color=#eeeedd>c</font>]]>
    </string>

    <!-- send feedback preset subject and email-->
    <string name="feedback_email">kbcv@informatik.uibk.ac.at</string>
    <string name="feedback_subject">Feedback on KBCV-App</string>
    <string name="title_feedback_dialog">Send feedback</string>

    <!-- help content-->
    <string-array name="eq_groups">
        <item>General</item>
        <item>Save/Import</item>
        <item>Symbols</item>
        <item>Equations</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="eq_general">
        Depending on your screen width you either see a tabbed view (&lt; 480dp) or two panels side by side (&#x2265; 480dp).
        The first tab or panel shows an edit area for variable  and function symbols. The second one
        contains an edit area for new equations and also shows a list of all current equations.
    </string>
    <string-array name="eq_save">
        <item>The import and save options are available in the overflow menu of
            the action bar (the three vertical dots at the far right end).</item>
        <item>Import: import equational systems from .trs oder .xml files. Files from the local KBCV folder are shown as a list.
        By default this list contains at least the standard group-theory example, but also all other equational systems that you ever from KBCV saved.</item>
        <item>Save: saves the current equational system to the local KBCV folder. A dialog will open where you have to enter a name for your file. </item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="eq_symbols">
        <item>Add: Pressing the + button opens a radial menu, where you can select the symbol you want to add. When adding
        a function symbol, you are also required to choose an arity after you selected a symbol.\nIf you want
        a symbol that is not contained in the list, use the button with the 3 dots (…) to open a dialog where you can
        enter a string that you want to use as symbol. The symbols that are shown in the radial menu by default can
            be changed in the settings.</item>
        <item>Delete: Longpress the symbol you want to delete, this makes the symbol draggable and turns the
        + button into a trash symbol. Now drag and drop the symbol onto the trash.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="eq_equations">
        <item>Creating equations:
        At the bottom of the equations view the edit area is located. The edit area holds a list of all previously defined variables and function
        symbols as draggable buttons. By dragging and dropping a symbol into the designated
        dropzone that symbol will be added to the equation. For functions with an arity greater
        than zero, the appropriate number of dropzones will be created. Symbols can also be dragged onto other symbols and thereby overwrite that part of
            the equation.\nWhen an equation is finished, i.e., containing no more dropzones, you can either
            press the ADD button or drop the equation into the list of existing equations by dragging
            it up at the ≈ sign.</item>
        <item>Editing and Deleting: You can select items in the list above the edit area and
            choose the desired action in the action bar. When choosing edit the equation will
            appear in the edit area at the bottom of the screen and you can start dragging
            different symbols onto it.
        </item>
    </string-array>


    <string-array name="completion_groups">
        <item>General</item>
        <item>Export TRS</item>
        <item>Gestures</item>
        <item>Automatic Completion</item>
        <item>Completeness Check</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="completion_general">
        Depending on your screen width you either see a tabbed view (&lt; 480dp) or two panels side by side (&#x2265; 480dp).
        The first tab or panel shows a list of all equations of the current equational system, the second one
        shows all rules of the current rewrite system.\nIn both views any number of items (equations or rules) can be selected and one of
        the inference rules of Knuth-Bendix completion can be applied to them, by using the appropriate action
        in the contextual action bar.
    </string>

    <string-array name="export_content">
        <item>The export action is available in the overflow menu of the App Bar. The current term rewrite system
        will be exported as a TRS file to the KBCV folder in Documents.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="gesture_content">
        <item>Orient\n Rightswipe equation to orient it from left to right, leftswipe it to orient from right to left.</item>
        <item>Simplify and Delete equation\nLongpress equation until it is draggable, drag it down and release it.
        This simplifies the equation as far as possible and then deletes it, if it has become trivial.</item>
        <item>Deduce\nLongpress rule until it is draggable, drag it onto the → of another rule and release. This adds
        all critical pairs that exist between those two rules to the equational system.</item>
        <item>Simplify, Compose, Collapse\nLongpress rule until it is draggable,
            drag it onto left- or right-hand side of another equation or rule.
            That term will be reduced with the rule, resulting in a Simplify, Compose, or Collapse action.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="automatic_comp_content">
        <item>Select automatic completion in the App Bar. It will either:\n
            &#8226; succeed and find a complete rewrite system,\n
            &#8226; fail because it can not orient a specific equation,\n
            &#8226; stop because it reached the maximum number of rounds.\nEither way the rewrite system
            that was reached during automatic completion will be displayed (whether it is complete or not).\nThe maximum number of rounds is initially set to 100
            and can be modified in the settings.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="check_content">
        <item>After every application of Orient or Delete, the app checks automatically for completeness.
        A message will then be displayed at the bottom of the app. This behaviour can be changed in the settings.\nYou can manually check for
        completeness by selecting the action in the App Bar.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="settings_groups">
        <item>Automatically Check for Completeness</item>
        <item>Cache Overlaps</item>
        <item>Rounds</item>
        <item>Variable Symbols</item>
        <item>Function Symbols</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="settings_autocomp">
        Turn off the automatic completeness check that is by
        default performed after every Delete- or Orient-action. This may be useful when you
        want to perform as much of the completion process manually as possible.
    </string>
    <string name="settings_cache">
        By default the app will remember which overlaps
        have already been considered and won’t add those equations repeatedly.
        You can turn of caching to test your own ability of finding critical pairs.
    </string>
    <string name="settings_rounds">
        Set the maximum number of rounds for automatic
        completion. An interesting option here is to set the number of rounds to 1. Then
        you can perform automatic completion round by round and view all intermediate
        equational systems and term rewrite systems.
    </string>
    <string name="settings_variables">
        Opens a dialog window where you can specify which
        variable symbols should be shown in the radial menu of the Equation Editor.
        Individual symbols have to be entered with a comma as delimiter, spaces being
        ignored. The maximum number of symbols that can be displayed in the radial
        menu is 6. Everything you enter after the sixth symbol will be ignored.
    </string>
    <string name="settings_functions">
        Opens a dialog window where you can specify which function symbols should appear in the radial menu
        of the Equation Editor. As with the variable symbols, characters can be entered
        into the edit dialog with a comma as delimiter and anything that exceeds the limit
        of six different symbols will be ignored.
    </string>

    <string-array name="precedence_groups">
        <item>General</item>
        <item>Add Rule</item>
        <item>Edit or Delete Rule</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="prec_general">
        We use the lexicographic path order (LPO) to determine whether an equation
        can be oriented into a rule, such that the resulting term rewrite system is still terminating.
        You can either provide the precedence for LPO yourself or leave it to the app, to
        figure out the necessary restrictions. This screen shows the ordering that is
        used at the moment to ensure the termination of the current term rewrite system. You
        can add, edit and delete rules as long as termination of the current rewrite
        system can be proved with this precedence.
    </string>
    <string name="prec_add">
        Adding a rule to the precedence works similarly to adding equations. At the bottom
        of the Precedence screen an edit area is located. Inside is a list of draggable buttons
        of all available function symbols and a stub of a new rule with a dropzone at each side.
        Function symbols can be dragged onto the dropzones (and onto other function symbols)
        to create a new rule. You can add a finished rule to the precedence by either pressing
        the add button or dragging it up on the &lt; sign.
    </string>
    <string name="prec_edit">
        To edit or delete an existing rule,
        you need to select it by tapping it and then choosing the appropriate action in the
        contextual action bar at the top of the screen.
        When selecting edit, the rule appears in the edit area and you
        can drag different function symbols onto the existing ones to change it.\nIf you
        to add a restriction that contradicts LPO termination, or if you trie to remove a rule that
        is needed for termination, the app will show an error message.
    </string>

    <string-array name="history_groups">
        <item>Undo/Redo</item>
        <item>History Dialog</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="history_undo">
        <item>The three activities Equation Editor, Completion, and Precedence, all feature undo and redo
            buttons in their respective action bars.</item> <!--TODO image-->
        <item>Tracked actions are:</item>
        <item>adding or deleting symbols</item>
        <item>adding, editing or deleting equations</item>
        <item>import of new equational systems</item>
        <item>every orient, simplify, delete, deduce, compose, collapse in the completion screen</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="history_dialog">
        Tapping the history entry in the Navigation Drawer opens a dialog showing all actions that were performed
        in the app since the last startup. Every entry is clickable and transforms the current
        equational system, symbols and rewrite system back to that state.
    </string>
</resources>